Francis P. Clark Sports Collection
University of Notre Dame Archives
Francis P. Clark Sports Collection
ca. 1853-1972
FCS
Clark, Francis P. (Francis Patrick), 1936-1979
200 reels of microfilm
University of Notre Dame Archives Notre Dame, Indiana 46556
Clark, Francis P. (Francis Patrick), 1936-1979
Scope and Content
Microfilm of various sporting newspapers made by Francis P. Clark: Sporting Life, Sporting News, Cleveland Plain Dealer Sports Pages, Baseball Players Chronicle, American Chronicle of Sports and Pastimes, Michigan Sportsman, New England Base Ballist, National Chronicle, New York Clipper, Official Baseball Record, and Weekly Baseball Guide; also Baseball Scrapbooks.
Background
A native of Kentucky, Francis Clark worked as university microfilmer at Notre Dame; when he died, he left his many collections to the University Archives.
Clark, Francis P. (Francis Patrick), 1936-1979; Baseball -- United States -- Periodicals.; Sports -- Periodicals.; Sporting life [microform].; The sporting news [microform].; The plain dealer [microform]. Baseball Players Chronicle [microform].; American Chronicle of Sports and Pastimes [microform].; Michigan Sportsman [microform].; New England base ballist [microform]: a weekly journal, an advocate of the national game, field sports and the drama.; National chronicle [microform]: journal of American sports and amusements.; New York Clipper [microform].; Official Baseball Record [microform].; Weekly Baseball Guide [microform].
Related Material
Francis P. Clark Collection
Francis P. Clark Papers
- Francis P. Clark Sports: Microfilm, MFCS
  - Sporting Life, 1883-1917; MFCS M3000; (29 reels)
  - Sporting News, 1916-1972; MFCS M3001; (111 reels)
  - Cleveland Plain Dealer Sports Pages, 1924-1962; MFCS M3002; (approximately 46 reels)
  - Baseball Players Chronicle (New York, NY), 1867/06-12 (June 6 - December 25); MFCS M3003; (1/2 reel)
  - American Chronicle of Sports & Pastimes, 1868/01-06 (Jan 2 - Jun 23); MFCS M3003; (1/2 reel)
  - Michigan Sportsman, 1952; MFCS M3004; (1 reel)
  - New England Base Ballist (Boston, MA), 1868 (Aug 6 - Dec 31); MFCS M3005; (1/2 reel)
  - National Chronicle (Boston, MA), 1869 (Jan 6 - Dec 25); MFCS M3005; (1 reel)
  - New York Clipper, 1857-59;1861-68;1878;1881-84 (1857, Jan 25 - 1859, Apr 9; 1861, Apr 20 - 1865, Apr 8; 1865, Apr 15 - 1868, Mar 28; 1878, Feb 9 - Dec 28; 1881, Mar 26 - 1882, Mar 18; 1882, Mar 25 - 1883, Mar 17; 1883, Mar 24 - 1884, Dec 27); MFCS M3006; (7 reels)
  - Official Baseball Record (New York, NY), 1885-1886 (1885, July 15 - 1886, October 9; MFCS M3007; (1 reel)
  - Weekly Baseball Guide (New York, NY), 1925; MFCS M3008; (1 reel)
  - Baseball Scrapbooks ca.1853-, 1882(-1912); MFCS M3009; (1 reel); Box scores, game writeups, season summaries and reviews, columns, and stories.
    A collection of microfilmed scrapbooks with newspaper clippings on amateurand professional baseball in the nineteenth and early twentieth centuries,with an emphasis on the 1870s. Contents are divided into ten discreteparts, apparently corresponding to the original scrapbooks or groups ofscrapbooks, as follows:
    Part 1: Season summaries and reviews [January 1871 - December 1878] andgame stories and box scores [April 1873 - September 1881]. Clippings derivefrom the New York Clipper, and cover the National Association and theNational League.
    Part 2: Game stories and box scores. Clippings derive mostly from dailynewspapers from National League cities, especially Chicago and St, Louis,with coverage emphasizing the National League. [May 1875 - May 1879].
    Part 3: Game stories and box scores from the New York Clipper, coveringmany college, amateur, and professional teams. [April 1870 - November 1877].
    Part 4: Articles on off-field developments in professional baseball,with anemphasis on the American League-National League war. Clippings derive fromvarious dailies, especially from New York. [December 1901 - January 1905].
    Part 5: Game stories and box scores. Clippings derive mostly from Bostondailies; coverage emphasizes the Boston National League club and other NewEngland area teams. [May 1879 - September 1882].
    Part 6: Articles on baseball from the New York Clipper [January 1879 -March 1881], followed by a few general baseball articles from the 1890s.
    Part 7: Articles on amateur and professional baseball from the New YorkClipper [March 1855 - January 1879], followed by a few articles on Bowler'sField Day in Cincinnati, 10 September 1907.
    Part 8: Game stories and box scores from the New York Clipper, withcoverage of many college, amateur, and professional teams. [July 1853 -March 1870].
    Part 9: Weekly baseball columns by William M. Rankin, mostly written as NewYork correspondent to The Sporting News [June 1904 - October 1912].
    Part 10: Game stories and box scores from the New York Clipper, coveringmany professional and amateur teams. [March 1878 - July 1882].
    [Courtesy of George Rugg, Joyce Sports Research Collection, University ofNotre Dame]